Alex Manrique

Software Engineer

Personal information

Email: contact@alexmanrique.com Website: www.alexmanrique.com

Software engineer fascinated by software development. Follow approved life cycle methodologies, create design documents, and perform program coding and testing. Resolve technical issues through debugging and research. Focused mainly on delivering clean code, loosely coupled and easy-to-scale.

Professional experience

Senior Java developer - Marketing team member @eDreams-Odigeo (January 2013 - Now)

- Designed and implemented an API using JAX-WS to expose eDreams search engine to Metasearchers like Kayak or Skyscanner. This API supports 20M searches per day and increased visits by 50% to eDreams web pages that lead to 20% more bookings in the last year.
- Developed search engine marketing software that improved Adwords advertisements effectiveness by 40% in the last year using J2EE and Google Adwords API (showing better prices in ads).

Senior Java Developer - Back-office team member @eDreams-Odigeo (February 2012 – December 2012)

- Implemented 3d-Secure over GlobalCollect that decreased fraud by 30% in all markets using J2EE. Increased unit testing coverage of legacy code using Testing and Mockito.
- Redesigned and implemented an automated process to refund bookings that didn't completed successfully to customers, using Quartz scheduling and Java. It reduced manual effort done by call center agents.
- Fixed bugs in JBoss and Dynamo legacy code platform and give support with old tools to final users.

Software Engineer @Safelayer Secure Communications S.A. (February 2009 – February 2012)

- Implemented a new e-authentication system that improved typical login, using a non-intrusive approach
 collecting multiple parameters like IP, browser and keystroke using Javascript in the front and Grails in
 the backend.
- Implemented a user interface made with ExtJS to show graphical information in Safelayer TrustedX platform.

Teacher @EnginyCat (October 2009 – June 2010)

 Selected for the EnginyCat 2009 program, promoted by the Generalitat de Catalunya addressed to the last year students with good marks.

Internship @Serveis Informatics Ia Caixa (July - December 2008)

 Collaboration with the Architecture department project of this financial entity collecting business requirements received by stakeholders.

Education

Computer Engineering, 2004-2009 @Barcelona School of Informatics (FIB), Technical University of Catalonia (UPC) in Barcelona (Spain)

- Equivalent to Bachelor of science + Master in Computer science. Graduate coursework: Software engineering; Databases; Algorithms; Computer Architecture; Operating systems.
- Graduated with Excellent in the final year degree project. Researched, designed and developed a new e-authentication system that became a product in Safelayer Secure Communications.

Skills

- · Languages: Java, SQL, Javascript, CSS
- Software: Jira, Intellij Idea, SoapUI, Firebug, Eclipse, VMWare
- Frameworks: Spring, Grails, Hibernate, Bootstrap
- Web/App Server: Tomcat, Apache, JBoss 4.3, JBoss 6.1
- Middleware/Webservices : JAX-WS ,SOAP, REST, JAX-RS
- Quality control: JUnit, PowerMock, TestNg, FindBugs, PMD, Checkstyle, CPD